1909 Hudson-Fulton Celebration Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 1. Postcards, 1901-1909; 1.0 linear feet 1 Box (Box 1)
  - Hudson Greeting Native Americans Postcard, Fraying of corners. Foxing across top of image. Crease in upper right of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Hudson greeting Native Americans along Hudson River.
  - Color Painted Portrait of Hudson Postcard, Fraying/damage to corners and edges where top image has chipped or worn away. Small scratch in upper right of image. Very faint cracking over image. Small stain on back bottom right. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of painted portrait of Henry Hudson.
  - Color Painted Portrait of Fulton Postcard, Slight fraying and damage along edges and corners where image has worn or chipped away more prominent along top. Small scratches over image. Foxing across back. Small tear on back top center where top layer has been removed. Small crack along upper right edge of back. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of painted portrait of Robert Fulton.
  - Half-Moon and Native Americans Postcard, Damage more prominent along top and left edge of front and right edge of back. Faint cracking over entire image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Hudson’s “Half-Moon” on Hudson River with Native Americans in boat.
  - Fulton’s Clermont on Hudson River Postcard (2 copies), Fraying along edges and corner where image has worn or chipped away on both. Faint cracking over entire image on both. Circular indentation on top center of one and creasing in bottom of image on same card. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Fulton’s “Clermont” travelling up Hudson River.
  - Half-Moon Leaving Amsterdam Postcard, Fraying along edges and corners. Small scratches in top center of image. Small stain on back top right edge. Slight discoloration of corners from previous storage. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Hudson’s “Half-Moon” leaving Amsterdam in Summer of 1609.
  - Fulton the First Postcard, Fraying along edges and corners. Discoloration and faint indentation of corners from previous storage. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of “Fulton the First” the first steam driven war vessel launched October 29, 1814.
  - Hudson-Fulton 5th Avenue Parade Postcard, Fraying along edges and corners. Creases in bottom two corners. Discoloration along back (Box 1)
    Depicts blue and white image of Hudson-Fulton Celebration Parade on 5th Avenue in NYC, overlaid with portraits of Hudson and Fulton and images of their two ships.
  - Lady Columbia Hudson-Fulton Postcard, Small crease in upper right corner. Discoloration along back edges. Discoloration of corners from previous storage. (Box 1)
    Depicts blue and white image of Lady Columbia holding up Hudson’s “Half-Moon” and Fulton’s “Clermont” in commemoration of Hudson-Fulton Celebration. Image overlaid with portraits of Hudson and Fulton.
  - Henry Hudson Sepia Portrait Postcard, Fraying of edges and corners. Creasing in top right corner. Some staining across back. (Box 1)
    Depicts sepia toned portrait of Henry Hudson below a group of flags.
  - Fulton Portrait and Quote Postcard, Fraying edges and corners. Creasing in bottom left of image. Small stains in upper right corner. (Box 1)
    Depicts sepia toned portrait of Robert Fulton above a quote. Quote reads: “The Liberty of the Seas will be the Happiness of the Earth”.
  - Fulton’s First Experiment on Conestoga Postcard, Fraying of corners and edges. Discoloration of corners from previous storage. Large crease in back bottom right corner. Faint staining across top of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts sepia toned image of Fulton on his first paddle boat on the Conestoga. Above image are portraits of Hudson and Fulton.
  - U.S. Man of War Postcard, Fraying of corners. Faint foxing across front and back. Discoloration of corners from previous storage. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of sailors onboard a U.S. Man of War. Postcard labelled “Souvenir of Hudson-Fulton Celebration. 1609-1909” along top. Copyright Enrique Muller 1906.
  - Light on the Past HF Celebration Postcard, Fraying and damage to edges where image has worn or chipped away. More prominent damage in top right corner. Crease in bottom right and bottom right corner. Ink has bled on back of card. Small spot where top layer of paper is missing in back bottom left corner. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of modern steamship shining spotlight on colonial ships, including Hudson’s “Half-Moon” on Hudson River.
  - Half-Moon Replica on Hudson Postcard, Fraying of edges and corners. Line of discoloration on left top to bottom of image. Faint indentations of corners from previous storage. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of “Half-Moon” replica created for Hudson-Fulton Celebration on Hudson River.
  - Half-Moon Sketch Postcard, Fraying of edges and corners. Large rip in top layer of paper on back, top of card. Large stain on back, top left and small stain on back, top right. Faint staining across front image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white sketch of Hudson’s “Half-Moon” on the Hudson River overlaid with portrait of Hudson.
  - Original Hendrik Hudson Flag Postcard, Staining along back, tope right edge and on back, bottom right. Small stains on back, right, center. Slight fraying of edges and corners. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of flag Hudson originally used during his journey up the Hudson River aboard the “Half-Moon”. Card also features a paragraph of information on the flag and what the letters on the flag represent.
  - Hudson Landing Postcard, Fraying around edges and corners. Faint staining in upper right of image. Circular indentation in upper right of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Henry Hudson’s landing from “Half-Moon”. Original label on postcard has been overlaid with new label for Hudson-Fulton Celebration 1909.
  - Baptism of Pocahontas Postcard, Fraying around edges and corners. Circular indentation in upper right of image. Small scratches over image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of the baptism of Pocahontas. Original label covered by stamp and new label for Hudson-Fulton Celebration 1909 placed along top edge.
  - Manhattan Series Envelope, Fraying, rips, and creasing along edges and corners. Paper is brittle. Some staining from USPS ink. Slight discoloration along edges. Top flap on back missing. (Box 1)
    Envelope for the sixteen card “Manhattan Series” Hudson-Fulton Celebration postcard collection. Envelope features list of postcards and their labels/captions.
  - Manhattan Series: Hudson Portrait Postcard, and creasing along edges and corners. Paper is brittle. Some staining from USPS ink. Slight discoloration along edges. Top flap on back missing. (Box 1)
    Depicts color portrait of Henry Hudson. Back of card features short bio on Hudson.
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton Portrait Postcard (Box 1)
    Depicts color portrait of Robert Fulton and quote. Back features short bio on Fulton.
  - Manhattan Series: Half-Moon Replica Postcard, Small stains on back middle and left. Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of replica of Hudson’s “Half-Moon” on the Hudson River. Back features short explanation about replica of ship.
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton at Clermont Manor Postcard, Small stain on back bottom center. Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of Robert Fulton entertaining guests at Clermont Manor. Back features short explanation about Clermont Manor.
  - Manhattan Series: Death of Hudson Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front of postcard. Small, faint staining along back bottome and top center. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of the death of Henry Hudson from the painting by Sir John Collier. Back features short bio for Henry Hudson regarding his death.
  - Manhattan Series: Jonathan Hulls’ Steamboat Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten note on front bottom of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of Jonathan Hulls’ Steamboat patented in 1737. Back features short explanation on Hulls’ Steamboat.
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton’s First Experiment Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front bottom of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of Fulton’s first experiment paddleboat on the Conestoga. Back features short explanation on Fulton’s experiment.
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton Homestead Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front bottom of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of the Fulton Homestead in Washington County, Pennsylvania. Back features a short explanation about Fulton’s homestead.
  - Manhattan Series: West Point Monument Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front bottom of postcard. Staining on back left both top and bottom and bottom center of back. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of the Hudson River view from the Battle Monument at West Point, NY. Back features short explanation on battle monument.
  - Manhattan Series: John Fitch’s Steamboat Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten note on front bottom of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of John Fitch’s Steamboat in Philadelphia in 1786. Back features short explanation on Fitch’s Steamboat.
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton’s Clermont Sketch Postcard, Faint crease down middle of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color sketch of Fulton’s own drawing of his ship the “Clermont”. Back features short blurb about Fulton’s sketch.
  - Manhattan Series: Lake Tear of the Clouds Postcard, Faint foxing along top of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Lake Tear of the Clouds, the source of the Hudson River. Back features short explanation on the lake.
  - Manhattan Series: Hudson Monument and Bridge Postcard, Stain on back bottom left. Faint staining on back from outline of front image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of both the Hudson Memorial Monument and Hudson Memorial Bridge. Back features short explanation on both monument and bridge.
  - Manhattan Series: Hudson’s Lower Manhattan Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of Lower Manhattan as Henry Hudson first saw it in 1609. Back features short explanation on Manhattan island in 1609.
  - Manhattan Series: Clermont’s First Trip Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front of postcard. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of Fulton’s “Clermont” on its first trip on August 17, 1807. Back features short explanation on the ship’s first trip.
  - Manhattan Series: Manhattan Today Postcard, Faint staining and indentation from previously erased handwritten notes on front of postcard. Faint crease visible through center of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of how Manhattan island looked in the present day in 1908-1909. Back features short explanation on Manhattan island and how Hudson would have viewed it.
  - Manhattan Series Envelope #2, Creasing and slight fraying of edges and corners. Small tears in upper right corner. Small stain on upper left corner and right center. Foxing across front and back of envelope. Second half of metal hardware on back missing. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series Set #2, Slight discoloration along edges of cards. (Box 1)
    Features all 16 postcards from Manhattan Series collection.
  - Manhattan Series Set #3, Slight damage in upper right of Hudson Portrait card where paper has chipped. Card also features small speck of residue on bottom of portrait. Slight damage to Half-Moon Replica card where top layer of paper has chipped on bottom right edge of image. Light staining along right edge of Fulton at Clermont Manor card. Small stain on bottom right of image on Clermont’s First Trip card. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series Set #4, Slight staining and fraying of edges of each. Slight fraying of corners. (Box 1)
    Features 15 of all 16 postcards from Manhattan Series collection. Missing West Point monument card.
  - Manhattan Series: Hudson Monument and Bridge Postcard #5 (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Clermont’s First Trip Postcard #5, Small stain along bottom right edge of image. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: John Fitch’s Steamboat Postcard #5 (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Jonathan Hulls’ Steamboat Postcard #5 (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton’s First Experiment Postcard #5, Faint staining in upper right corner of image. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton’s Clermont Sketch Postcard #5, Faint scratches on top left and right of image. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Clermont’s First Trip Postcard #6 (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton Homestead Postcard #5 (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Hudson Portrait Postcard #5, Very slight creasing in top and bottom right corner. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton Portrait Postcard #5, Very faint creasing in bottom two corners. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Death of Hudson Postcard #, Faint stain across back and bottom front. Small crease along bottom center edge. Slight fraying of edges and corners. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Half-Moon Replica Postcard #5, Slight fraying of edges and corners. Damage to upper right corner more pronounced as first layer of paper is missing. Slight indentation in corners from previous storage. Crease in bottom left corner. (Box 1)
  - Manhattan Series: Fulton at Clermont Manor Postcard #5, Faint discoloration in bottom right corner. Small stain in upper left corner. (Box 1)
  - Grant’s Tomb Crowd Postcard, Discoloration and indentations in corners from previous storage. Faint scratches down the left edge of image. Small indentations along top right of image. Small stain on back left edge. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of crowd gather in Grant’s Tomb NY to view the Hudson Fulton Celebration Water Parade on the Hudson River on September 25, 1909.
  - Riverside Drive Crowd Postcard, Discoloration and faint indentations in corners from previous storage. Large crease in upper right corner of image. Scratches over top right and top center of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of crowd gathered along Riverside Drive awaiting the arrival of the “Half-Moon” and “Clermont” on the Hudson River on September 25, 1909.
  - Arrival of Clermont at Riverside Drive Postcard, Stain in upper right of image. Large crease from upper right to middle of image. Small crease in middle to upper left of image. Scratches across top of image to middle. Large crease in bottom left corner of image. Faint indentations and discoloration in corners from previous storage. Large crease runs across bottom of card. Small crease in bottom right corner. Residue of unknown substance on back top center. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of the “Clermont” upon arrival at 110th Street and Riverside Drive for Hudson-Fulton Celebration on the Hudson River.
  - Arrival of Half-Moon at Riverside Drive Postcard, Two deep scratches from top center to center of image. Deep scratch from top right to center right of image. Scratch from top left to center left of image. Faint indentations in corners from previous storage. Small faint scratches over entire image. Back print shows through front top of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of “Half-Moon” upon arrival at 110th Street and Riverside Drive for Hudson-Fulton Celebration on the Hudson River.
  - Naval Parade Postcard, Deep creases in bottom left corner. Faint indentations in other three corners from previous storage. Large scratch across bottom left to middle of image. Small faint scratches over entire image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Naval Parade on Hudson River during the Hudson-Fulton Celebration 1909.
  - German Marines in Military Parade Postcard, Small stain along top right to middle of image. Slight fraying of corners. Small stain on top right of image. Small creases in top left of image. Very small tears along top right edge of back. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white image of German Marines marching in the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Military Parade on September 30, 1909.
  - French Sailors in Military Parade Postcard, Striations across entire image. Rounding of right two corners of card. Small creases in bottom left corner. Faint staining across top of back. Faint striations across image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of French Sailors marching in the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Military Parade on September 30, 1909.
  - Dutch Marines in Military Parade Postcard, Faint striations across image. Slight fraying of corners. Small faint stains on back top right and left. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Dutch Marines marching in Hudson-Fulton Celebration Military Parade on September 30, 1909.
  - Italian Marine in Military Parade Postcard, Faint striations across image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Italian Marines marching in Hudson-Fulton Celebration Military Parade on September 30, 1909.
  - Largest American Flag Parade Postcard, Striations across entire image. Slight fraying of edges and corners. Faint staining along left and top edge of back. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of 200 U.S. War Veterans carrying the largest American flag at the time measuring 100x60 feet in Hudson-Fulton Celebration Military Parade.
  - Old Broadway Sleigh Float Postcard, Faint striations across entire image. Small creases in corners. Faint crease from top to bottom right of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white image of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration parade float representing the “Ole Broadway Sleigh” in Historical Parade on September 28, 1909.
  - Storming of Stony Point Float Postcard, Very faint striations across top of image. Creasing in corners. Faint stain on bottom right of back. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white image of Hudson-Fulton Celebration float representing the “Storming of Stony Point” in Historical Parade on September 28. 1909.
  - Reception of Peter Stuyvesant Float Postcard, Large stains from top to bottom right of image. Small crease in corners. Very faint staining across back. Faint striations across top of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Hudson-Fulton Celebration float representing the Reception given to Peter Stuyvesant in 1647 in Historical Parade of September 28, 1909.
  - George III and Philipse Manor House Float Postcard, Faint crease from top to bottom right of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white image of two Hudson-Fulton Celebration floats representing the destruction of the Statue of George III on July 9, 1776 and the Philipse Manor House in Yonkers erected in 1686. Both floats were featured in Historical Parade on September 28, 1909.
  - Hungarian Societies Parade Postcard, Small crease in bottom left corner. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Hungarian Societies marching in Hudson-Fulton Celebration Historical Parade on September 28, 1909.
  - Swedish Societies Parade Postcard (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Swedish Societies marching in Hudson-Fulton Celebration Historical Parade on September 28, 1909.
  - Arrival of Clermont at Riverside Drive Postcard #2, Striations across image. Fraying of corners and edges. Faint crease from top to bottom right of image. (Box 1)
  - Naval Parade Postcard #2, Striations across image. Fraying of corners and edges. Ship in top layer of image in upper right corner. Very small piece of residue substance on upper left edge of image. (Box 1)
  - Arrival of Half-Moon at Riverside Drive Postcard, Faint striations across image. Small stain on back upper left corner. Fraying of corners and edges. Discoloration along back bottom edge. Small scratches on right center to bottom of image. Faint crease from top to bottom right of image. (Box 1)
  - Half-Moon Float Postcard, Large crease in bottom right of image. Faint crease from top to bottom right of image. Discoloration of right and left side of image. Fraying of corners and edges. Staining across back. Very small piece of unknown substance on left center of image. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Hudson-Fulton Celebration float representing the “Half-Moon” in the Historical Parade on September 28, 1909.
  - Washington’s Oath Float Postcard, Faint crease from top to bottom right of image. Fraying of corners and edges. Small faint scratches on left center of photo. Small stains along right edges of image. Discoloration along back bottom edge. (Box 1)
    Depicts black and white photo of Hudson-Fulton Celebration float representing Washington taking his oath of office as the first president of the United States in Historical Parade on September 28, 1909.
  - Hudson Trading on Manhattan Island Postcard, Faint scratches in each corner possibly from previous storage. Fraying of corners and edges. Staining across back top edge and back left center. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Henry Hudson trading with Native Americans on Manhattan Island.
  - Fulton Portrait with Model Clermont Postcard #2, Faint scratches across image. Faint indentation in corners from previous storage. Large crease in bottom left corner. Fraying of corners and edges. Very faint staining across back. Small crease in right center bottom edge. (Box 1)
  - Steamer Clermont Postcard, Bright pink staining across back. Fraying of edges and corners. Several deep creases in bottom left corner. Crease in upper left corner. Stain across top right to center from USPS ink. Two pieces of tape on back upper right and bottom right corner. (Box 1)
    Depicts color image of Fulton and Clermont preparing for journey up the Hudson.
  - Hudson Fulton Celebration Clermont Postcard, Discoloration around edges of image and colors significantly faded. Faint scratches over entire image. Slight fraying of corners and edges. Staining on back along top edge and in upper left to center. (Box 1)
    Depicts sketch of Fulton and “Clermont” over background of Dutch flag. Back features short blurb about Hudson’s journey up the Hudson River while flying the Dutch flag.
  - Hudson Fulton Celebration Half-Moon Postcard, Staining around edges of image. Stain in upper right of image. Faint scratches over entire image. Fraying of corners and edges. (Box 1)
    Depicts golden sketch of Hudson and “Half-Moon” over background of Dutch flag. Back features short blurb about Hudson’s journey up the Hudson River while flying the Dutch flag.
  - Henry Hudson and Half-Moon River Discovery Postcard, Various small, faint scratches across image. Faint staining from USPS ink across top of image. Faint crease along left, center edge. Fraying of corners and edges. Faint staining along back edge. Small stain on bottom right corner. Faint crease along right center edge. Small stain on upper right corner. (Box 1)
    Depicts color portrait of Henry Hudson over image of “Half-Moon” on Hudson. Design copyright 1909, W.M. Miller, NY. Wording along top explains how Hudson discovered river in 1609.
  - Texturized Color Koehler Clermont Journey Postcard #2, Fraying of corners and edges. Faint staining on upper left of image. (Box 1)
  - Hudson “Half-Moon” Landing Postcard, Fraying of corners and edges. (Box 1)
    Depicts color drawing of Hudson landing on Hudson River bank from “Half-Moon” aided by Native Americans. Edges are gilded.
  - Dock Landing of Clermont Postcard #2, Fraying and staining of corners and edges. (Box 1)
  - Color Henry Hudson Memorial Bridge Postcard #3, Fraying of corners and edges. Faint staining across back. (Box 1)
    Depicts color portrait of Henry Hudson with background of Henry Hudson Memorial Bridge and ships on Hudson River.